Guide to the Christian Anti-Communism Crusade Collection ARS.0079
Archive of Recorded Sound
Christian Anti-Communism Crusade Collection
1964
ARS.0079
Christian Anti-Communism Crusade.
1 box: 15 7" open reel tapes
Archive of Recorded Sound
Fifteen open reel tapes produced by the Christian Anti-Communism Crusade in 1964 containing lectures and panel discussions from a workshop held in Washington, D.C.
Access
Open for research; material must be requested at least two business days in advance of intended use. Contact the Archive for assistance.
Scope and Contents
Recordings produced by the Christian Anti-Communism Crusade in 1964, containing lectures and panel discussions about politics, foreign policy, and anti-Communist activism. Many of the lectures are by CACC founder Fred Schwarz (1913-2009), who organized several five-day workshops (called "schools") around the country beginning in 1960. This collection is a complete set of what was referred to as "Washington D.C. School Tapes," purchased in October 1964 from the Crusade, then based in Houston, Texas. The tapes are marked 1-WDC-64 through 15-WDC-64.
Indexing Terms
Schwarz, Fred, 1913-; Drakeford, John W.; Lowry, Charles Wesley; Rowe, David Nelson, 1905-; Philbrick, Herbert A. (Herbert Arthur), 1915-1993; Bouscaren, Anthony Trawick; Wood, Doris; Menocal, Serafin; Atkinson, James; Cold War.; Communism.; Speeches, addresses, etc.
- 1-WDC-64, 1964; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Fred Schwarz "Communist Philosophy"; John Drakeford "Communism and the Family"
- 2-WDC-64, 1964; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
  Fred Schwarz "Communist Philosophy"; Charles Lowry "The Ideology of Freedom Versus the Ideology of Communism"
- 3-WDC-64, 1964; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
  Fred Schwarz "The Communist Party"; Serafin Menocal "Communism in Cuba"
- 4-WDC-64, 1964; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
  Fred Schwarz "Communist Grant Organizations"; James Atkinson "Communist Military"
- 5-WDC-64, 1964; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
  Fred Schwarz "How To Debate With Communists," "What Can I Do? 2"
- 6-WDC-64, 1964; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
  John Drakeford "The Communist Manifesto"; Fred Schwarz "Grand Design for Conquest"
- 7-WDC-64, 1964; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
  David Rowe "Sino-Soviet Conflict"; Fred Schwarz "Communist Recruitment"
- 8-WDC-64, 1964; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
  Charles Lowry "Christian Answer to Communism"; Fred Schwarz "Communism and Violence"
- 9-WDC-64, 1964; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
  Herb Philbrick "Communism And Youth"; Fred Schwarz "Principles of Anti-Communist Activities"
- 10-WDC-64, 1964; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
  Panel on "Public Speaking"; McDowell "Communism And Labor"
- 11-WDC-64, 1964; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
  Panel on "Work on Campus"; "Soviet Foreign Policy"
- 12-WDC-64, 1964; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
  Panel on "Public Relations"; "Communism in Brazil"
- 13-WDC-64, 1964; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
  Panel on "Anti-Communism Organizations"; "Communism in British Guiana"
- 14-WDC-64, 1964; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
  [Anthony] Bouscaren "Communism in Southeast Asia"; Doris Wood "Work in Local Community"
- 15-WDC-64, 1964; 1 7" open reel tape (Audio 1)
  Banquet Short Talks; Banquet Address